<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Loyola CS Systems Guide – virtual machines</title><link>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/tags/virtual-machines/</link><description>Recent content in virtual machines on Loyola CS Systems Guide</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/tags/virtual-machines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Virtualization</title><link>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/virtualization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/virtualization/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We are now able to host Xen and Windows Hyper-V virtual servers in the
department. We can host these with a dedicated public IP address
(justification is required to obtain one) or private IP addresses which
would be visible when you connect via the Loyola VPN. Given our present
resource limitations, we can only provide virtual machines on a limited
basis, primarily for faculty and student research/outreach projects.
Please send your requests to the vm alias (see
&lt;code>getting-help&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;ldquo;doc&amp;rdquo;}) and make sure you include
the following information:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>name&lt;/strong>: your full name&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>university e-mail address&lt;/strong>: we will not give virtual machines to
anyone who is not part of the Loyola community, although we will
allow same to be used by outsiders, provided there is a Loyola
contact.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>alternate e-mail address&lt;/strong>: where we can find you in case you
decide not to read your Loyola e-mail (or you're not getting your
messages!)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>duration&lt;/strong>: amount of time in months for your project, or
permanent (in general, permanent machines will be given only with
highly sound justification.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>RAM&lt;/strong>: required RAM in 256MB increments; large allocations are
rarely given. We'll prioritize requests that are smaller than
512MB.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>disk space&lt;/strong>: required storage in 10GB increments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>desired OS&lt;/strong>: We recommend Ubuntu server edition but can support
many others. At present, we do not support any OS that requires a
license key or activation (except Windows on our new Hyper-V racks).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>desired hostname&lt;/strong>: may be requested in one cs, math, etl, cslabs
(a private zone), all of which are subdomains of luc.edu. For
example, if you want the hostname gkt in the domain etl.luc.edu, you
would ask for gkt.etl.luc.edu&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>public or private static IP&lt;/strong>: You must say public or private. We
will generally be asking you (especially if you're a student) to
start with a private IP address. This in most cases will require you
to choose the domain cslabs.luc.edu, which only resolves within
Loyola proper.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>type of virtual machine&lt;/strong>: Xen, VMware, Hyper-V program. You would
only need VMware if you want to host a Windows VM but we presently
have no plans to support Windows, per our emphasis on freely
available OS technology without activation requirements.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>number of CPUs&lt;/strong>: we are only able to support 1 for most requests
at this time.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>