<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Loyola CS Systems Guide – Windows</title><link>https://softwaresystemslaboratory.github.io/SSL-Hugo-Website/tags/windows/</link><description>Recent content in Windows on Loyola CS Systems Guide</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://softwaresystemslaboratory.github.io/SSL-Hugo-Website/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Windows Desktop Support</title><link>https://softwaresystemslaboratory.github.io/SSL-Hugo-Website/docs/its-services/windows-desktop-support/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://softwaresystemslaboratory.github.io/SSL-Hugo-Website/docs/its-services/windows-desktop-support/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Note: As of June 30, 2010, we no longer provide desktop computing
support in the department.
These needs are addressed by the ITS desktop
support group.
This change does not prevent users from establishing their own standalone desktop setup but we are focusing our efforts on non-commodity needs that are synergistic with advanced teaching/research needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h1 id="windows-desktop-support">Windows Desktop Support&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Windows desktop matters are handled by ITS.
If you are experiencing trouble with Windows labs and other ITS issues, please open a support ticket at &lt;a href="https://luc.saasit.com/">https://luc.saasit.com/&lt;/a>.
Linux and Mac desktop matters are the responsibility of individual faculty.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Windows Labs</title><link>https://softwaresystemslaboratory.github.io/SSL-Hugo-Website/docs/its-services/windows-labs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://softwaresystemslaboratory.github.io/SSL-Hugo-Website/docs/its-services/windows-labs/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;/div>
&lt;h1 id="windows-labs">Windows Labs&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>With our partner, Loyola Information Technology Services (ITS), we
ensure that CS and Math/Stats software needs are formally requested from
ITS. This allows us to focus on advanced computing needs (in particular,
Linux and server-side applications) and ensure ubiquitous access to
Windows labs via the Loyola login ID.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Faculty may request additional software by visiting
&lt;a href="http://www.luc.edu/its/resources/technologypurchases/hardwaresoftwarereviewprocess/">ITS&lt;/a>,
or by sending an e-mail to the &lt;em>windows&lt;/em> alias (see
&lt;code>getting-help&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;ldquo;doc&amp;rdquo;}). In the latter case, the
lab manager (Miao Ye) will fill in a software request on your behalf.
You are encouraged to submit requests one month before the end of the
current term, if you need the software in the summer or following term.
For example, if you need software in Fall 2009, consider getting your
request in by April of 2008 (one month before the Spring 2008 term
ends). You should also indicate in your request whether you are willing
to help test the software after it becomes available. We cannot be held
responsible for late requests or requests that do not have a designated
faculty member interested in testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Again, because the Windows hardware and software are now maintained by
ITS, we ask that all issues you encounter be reported, no matter how
trivial. If you discover broken hardware and/or software, use the &lt;a href="http://www.luc.edu/helpdesk/">ITS
Help Desk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>