<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Systems Docs – alliances</title><link>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/tags/alliances/</link><description>Recent content in alliances on Systems Docs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/tags/alliances/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Academic Alliances</title><link>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/academic-alliances-programs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/academic-alliances-programs/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The department has active memberships in various academic alliance
programs:&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="microsoft-developer-network-msdn-aa">Microsoft Developer Network (MSDN AA)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Computer Science Department is a member of the MSDN Academic
Alliance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you already know your login info, visit
&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/msdn-loyola-chicago-cs">http://bit.ly/msdn-loyola-chicago-cs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this membership, any student who takes a computer science course
will have an account to download the latest development tools, operating
systems, server software, documentation, and technical references at
his/her fingertips for free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you need to retrieve your username and password, try this:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Username and Password: Your username is your Loyola email address.
The email address must be entered in the form of &lt;em>xyz@luc.edu&lt;/em>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;em>Sign In&lt;/em> button on the top right. Click the button in
&lt;em>forgot your username or password?&lt;/em> section for a reminder. Check
your Loyola email to get your password.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Please note that the MSDNAA &lt;em>excludes&lt;/em> Microsoft Office. All Loyola
University Chicago students have access to Microsoft Office 365. See
&lt;a href="http://www.luc.edu/its/exchange/about_office_365.shtml">http://www.luc.edu/its/exchange/about_office_365.shtml&lt;/a> for details.
(This does not cover faculty and staff, who need to get their own
subscription.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a Mac running OS X, you can download VMware (see below) and
install it. Then install Windows and other Windows applications as
usual.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="vmware-academic-program-vmap">VMware Academic Program (VMAP)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Computer Science Department is a member of the VMware Academic
Program (VMAP).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>VMware provides VMware Workstation and other virtualization products,
which are helpful for users who may want to run Windows, Linux, and
other operating systems on their Windows, Mac OS X, or Linux computers.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Mac users should download VMware Fusion.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows or Linux users should download VMware Workstation.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you already know your login info, visit
&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/vmap-loyola-chicago-cs">http://bit.ly/vmap-loyola-chicago-cs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="apple-developer-program">Apple Developer Program&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Computer Science Department is a member of the Apple Developer
Progarm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Information can be found at
&lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/programs/ios/university/gettingstarted/">https://developer.apple.com/programs/ios/university/gettingstarted/&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This program requires a bit of special handling, so please contact the
lab manager at &lt;code>people&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;ldquo;doc&amp;rdquo;} to be enrolled.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>