<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Loyola CS Systems Guide – Department Services</title><link>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/</link><description>Recent content in Department Services on Loyola CS Systems Guide</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Content Management</title><link>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/content-management-and-hosting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/content-management-and-hosting/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>We no longer provide support for static web page serving, PHP, and CGI
scripting. We realize that this might be an inconvenience to some.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="temporary-hosting-using-a-vm">Temporary Hosting using a VM&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For students doing project work, we can provide temporary virtual machines running on VMWare or Windows Hyper-V.
These VMs can be configured with a web server that is visible internally to Loyola.
See &lt;a href="../virtualization/">Virtualization&lt;/a> for additional information.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="alternatives">Alternatives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We encourage those who need to set up web sites to consider establishing
web hosting account via one of the many providers out there.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="blogging-platforms">Blogging platforms&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you are just looking to maintain a simple site that allows for page creation and blog posts, the best options are blogging platforms, such as &lt;a href="https://wordpress.com">Wordpress&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://ghost.org">Ghost&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://micro.blog">Micro.Blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="linode">Linode&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We actually use dedicated virtual machines for some department hosting needs. A particularly nice option is &lt;a href="https://linode.com">Linode&lt;/a>. For as little as $5-$10 a month, you can get a dedicated virtual machine with any Linux distribution you like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This option is primarily for more technical users who know Unix/Linux system administration (and commands).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="google-apps">Google Apps&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We do have Google Apps available in the department, which includes Blogger and Google Sites. While both of these options are starting to look/feel a bit dated, they nevertheless are easy to use and require virtually no configuration (except for us to enable your site).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Facilities</title><link>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/facilities/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/facilities/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="general-computing-labs">General Computing Labs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The department has general computer laboratories at the Lake Shore and
Water Tower Campuses. They are three windows labs and one free/open
source laboratory (at Water Tower Campus only) running Ubuntu Linux. The
Windows labs are managed by Information Technology Services (ITS) with
software requests submitted regularly by the department.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>::: index
pair: research; Internet-2
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="internet-2">Internet-2&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The CS Department was part of a successful team that received funding to
bring Internet-2 to Loyola University Chicago as a whole. This
next-generation Internet allows students within the department to
explore ideas such as cluster computing, grid computing, Internet
telephony, and distributed scientific application development. In
addition to Internet-2, the university maintains a high-speed optical
network/ring that connects all of the Loyola campuses (LSC, WTC, and
Loyola University Medical Center).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>::: index
pair: research; Windows HPC Cluster
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="windows-hpc-cluster">Windows HPC Cluster&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Drs. Putonti and Thiruvathukal operate two Windows HPC clusters: an
80-node dual-core Opteron cluster by Rackable Systems and a 24-node
dual-core Xeon cluster by Dell. Both clusters feature high-speed
Ethernet and/or Infiniband. These clusters are housed in the ITS data
center.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>::: index
pair: research; GPGPU pair: Emerging Technologies Laboratory; GPGPU
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="gpgpu-server">GPGPU Server&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Our new GPGPU Server was set up at our ETL. It is SuperServer
7046GT-TRF-TC4 with 2 x Intel Xeon Quad-Core (16 logical processors),
96GB RAM, 4 x NVIDIA® Tesla C2075 GPUs. Please read our
&lt;code>gpgpu-server&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;ldquo;doc&amp;rdquo;} guide on how to get
started.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>::: index
single: Emerging Technologies Laboratory
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="emerging-technologies-laboratory">Emerging Technologies Laboratory&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://www.etl.luc.edu">ETL&lt;/a> is a growing presence for experimental
computer science and engineering projects. This laboratory supports many
experimental computing needs and is a place where students can explore
ideas not covered directly in any particular class. Virtualization,
embedded systems, green computing, and mobile development take place
here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>::: index
single: wireless
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="wireless">Wireless&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The entire department (faculty offices, computer labs, emerging
technologies lab, and halls) are covered by 802.11g Wireless LAN.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="research-data-center">Research Data Center&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Loyola University Chicago&amp;rsquo;s Research Data Center (RDC) is a
1,000-square-foot facility dedicated to support research and funded
grants projects, provides a secure home for the computational clusters
and related equipment used by our research community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The RDC (opened in 2010) delivers a high availability computing
environment for research projects. This facility is equipped with power
protection, including an uninterruptible power supply and a back-up
generator. Multiple computer room air conditioner (CRAC) units provide
redundant cooling for the space, and a structured cabling design allows
for high-speed network connectivity. In addition to fire protection,
additional safety and security elements for the RDC include keycard
access, camera surveillance, and environmental monitoring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sized to accommodate moderate growth, several research initiatives are
currently taking advan- tage of the space, which at present houses three
research clusters and over 100 nodes. Additionally, collaborative
research efforts with other participating institutions and/or
organizations have full access and connectivity to Internet2 via the
Metropolitan Research &amp;amp; Education Network (MREN) to accommodate high
bandwidth applications, data transmissions, and computational require-
ments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A steering committee, made up of senior administrators, faculty, and ITS
professionals, is re- sponsible for reviewing, evaluating, and
recommending strategies, plans, and policies governing the use of the
RDC resources. Loyola&amp;rsquo;s RDC is managed by Information Technology
Services (ITS) in partnership with the university&amp;rsquo;s Facilities
Department.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Drs. Thiruvathukal, Läufer, and Putonti have a general-purpose 80-node
computing cluster that runs a mix of Windows HPC Server and the ROCKS
clustering software.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: People</title><link>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/people/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/people/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>Needs updates.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>We pride ourselves in paying attention to human interaction. While the
support aliases described in the previous section must be used whenever
you want something to be done, you may want to know something about the
major roles in our department that are applicable to computing.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Chairperson&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="http://laufer.cs.luc.edu">Konstantin Läufer&lt;/a>.
Please contact the Chairperson with any suggestions you have for
improvement, especially when itcomes to computing matters. The
chairperson has the ultimate reponsibility for all department
matters, especially the departmental computing budget.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Computing Director&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="http://thiruvathukal.com">George K.
Thiruvathukal&lt;/a>. Pleasecontact the
Computing Director with any suggestions you have for improvement or
with technical support questions. The Computing Director is
ultimatelyresponsible for the implementation of all computing
initiatives for the department, in particular those that support our
teaching and research missions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Lab Manager&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="http://www.luc.edu/cs/people/staff/yemiao.shtml">Miao
Ye&lt;/a>. The Lab
Manager is ultimately responsible for the implementation of the
intiaitives as defined by the Computing Director (who consults with
the Chairperson). Because there is onlyone Lab Manager at the
moment, it is important to recognize that he/she works to support
all requests in a timely manner but may not be ableto resolve your
problem immediately. Please allow 24-48 hours for a response to any
non-emergency need.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Computing Committee&lt;/strong>: &lt;a href="http://thiruvathukal.com">George K.
Thiruvathukal&lt;/a> (Computing Director and
Committee Chair), &lt;a href="http://laufer.cs.luc.edu">Konstantin Läufer&lt;/a>,
Prof. Stephen Doty, and two new members to be determined (one more
faculty and one more student member). The Compting Committee meets
at least twice per academic year and drafts recommendations and
resolutions for future computing initiatives that support the
department's teaching and researchmission and those of
collaborating departments. The commitee's proceedings are reported
to the Chairperson.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>In most cases, you should contact the &lt;strong>Lab Manager&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: User Accounts</title><link>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/user-accounts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/user-accounts/</guid><description>
&lt;p>All students and faculty are given accounts in the CS department. Your
account is intended for your use only. Please change your intial
password immediately on first use to improve security. (We are able to
determine when a password has not been changed from the default and will
lock accounts after a certain period.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We presently lack a self-service mechanism to the PAM service maintained
by ITS for resetting your password. In any event, given the manageable
number of users, you can send a request to the accounts alias to have
your password reset for you. Since we set up all of our accounts to
match your university login ID, it is our policy to send your
replacement password to your Loyola e-mail address. You may also opt to
meet the lab manager in person but must show your Loyola or a
government-issued id with your photo on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To reset your password, you should log into &lt;code>random.cs.luc.edu&lt;/code> using a
secure shell client (a.k.a. SSH) and use the passwd program to reset it.
We recommend that you are on campus when you need to change your
password.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Virtualization</title><link>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/virtualization/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/virtualization/</guid><description>
&lt;p>We are now able to host Xen and Windows Hyper-V virtual servers in the
department. We can host these with a dedicated public IP address
(justification is required to obtain one) or private IP addresses which
would be visible when you connect via the Loyola VPN. Given our present
resource limitations, we can only provide virtual machines on a limited
basis, primarily for faculty and student research/outreach projects.
Please send your requests to the vm alias (see
&lt;code>getting-help&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;ldquo;doc&amp;rdquo;}) and make sure you include
the following information:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>name&lt;/strong>: your full name&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>university e-mail address&lt;/strong>: we will not give virtual machines to
anyone who is not part of the Loyola community, although we will
allow same to be used by outsiders, provided there is a Loyola
contact.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>alternate e-mail address&lt;/strong>: where we can find you in case you
decide not to read your Loyola e-mail (or you're not getting your
messages!)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>duration&lt;/strong>: amount of time in months for your project, or
permanent (in general, permanent machines will be given only with
highly sound justification.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>RAM&lt;/strong>: required RAM in 256MB increments; large allocations are
rarely given. We'll prioritize requests that are smaller than
512MB.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>disk space&lt;/strong>: required storage in 10GB increments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>desired OS&lt;/strong>: We recommend Ubuntu server edition but can support
many others. At present, we do not support any OS that requires a
license key or activation (except Windows on our new Hyper-V racks).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>desired hostname&lt;/strong>: may be requested in one cs, math, etl, cslabs
(a private zone), all of which are subdomains of luc.edu. For
example, if you want the hostname gkt in the domain etl.luc.edu, you
would ask for gkt.etl.luc.edu&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>public or private static IP&lt;/strong>: You must say public or private. We
will generally be asking you (especially if you're a student) to
start with a private IP address. This in most cases will require you
to choose the domain cslabs.luc.edu, which only resolves within
Loyola proper.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>type of virtual machine&lt;/strong>: Xen, VMware, Hyper-V program. You would
only need VMware if you want to host a Windows VM but we presently
have no plans to support Windows, per our emphasis on freely
available OS technology without activation requirements.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>number of CPUs&lt;/strong>: we are only able to support 1 for most requests
at this time.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Docs: Academic Alliances</title><link>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/academic-alliances-programs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/academic-alliances-programs/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The department has active memberships in various academic alliance
programs:&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="microsoft-developer-network-msdn-aa">Microsoft Developer Network (MSDN AA)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Computer Science Department is a member of the MSDN Academic
Alliance.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you already know your login info, visit
&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/msdn-loyola-chicago-cs">http://bit.ly/msdn-loyola-chicago-cs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this membership, any student who takes a computer science course
will have an account to download the latest development tools, operating
systems, server software, documentation, and technical references at
his/her fingertips for free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you need to retrieve your username and password, try this:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Username and Password: Your username is your Loyola email address.
The email address must be entered in the form of &lt;em>xyz@luc.edu&lt;/em>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Click the &lt;em>Sign In&lt;/em> button on the top right. Click the button in
&lt;em>forgot your username or password?&lt;/em> section for a reminder. Check
your Loyola email to get your password.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Please note that the MSDNAA &lt;em>excludes&lt;/em> Microsoft Office. All Loyola
University Chicago students have access to Microsoft Office 365. See
&lt;a href="http://www.luc.edu/its/exchange/about_office_365.shtml">http://www.luc.edu/its/exchange/about_office_365.shtml&lt;/a> for details.
(This does not cover faculty and staff, who need to get their own
subscription.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have a Mac running OS X, you can download VMware (see below) and
install it. Then install Windows and other Windows applications as
usual.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="vmware-academic-program-vmap">VMware Academic Program (VMAP)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Computer Science Department is a member of the VMware Academic
Program (VMAP).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>VMware provides VMware Workstation and other virtualization products,
which are helpful for users who may want to run Windows, Linux, and
other operating systems on their Windows, Mac OS X, or Linux computers.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Mac users should download VMware Fusion.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Windows or Linux users should download VMware Workstation.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If you already know your login info, visit
&lt;a href="http://bit.ly/vmap-loyola-chicago-cs">http://bit.ly/vmap-loyola-chicago-cs&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="apple-developer-program">Apple Developer Program&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Computer Science Department is a member of the Apple Developer
Progarm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Information can be found at
&lt;a href="https://developer.apple.com/programs/ios/university/gettingstarted/">https://developer.apple.com/programs/ios/university/gettingstarted/&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This program requires a bit of special handling, so please contact the
lab manager at &lt;code>people&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;ldquo;doc&amp;rdquo;} to be enrolled.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Durian GPGPU Server</title><link>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/gpgpu-server/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/gpgpu-server/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>This page needs improvement.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The CS and Mathematics departments subscribe to Google Apps for Your&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="gpgpu-server">GPGPU Server&lt;/h1>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>After you log in the server, please run the following command to
install the SDK in your home directory:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ cp_gpusdk
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;p>This will result in a folder being created in
~/NVIDIA_GPU_Computing_SDK,&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Compiling the examples:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>$ cd ~/NVIDIA_GPU_Computing_SDK/C
$ make
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Run the &lt;code>deviceQuery&lt;/code> demo to see the GPGPU device(s).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>::: literalinclude
devicequery.txt
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>See
&lt;a href="http://developer.download.nvidia.com/compute/cuda/3_2/docs/Getting_Started_Linux.pdf">http://developer.download.nvidia.com/compute/cuda/3_2/docs/Getting_Started_Linux.pdf&lt;/a>
for additional details.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Docs: Google Apps</title><link>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/google-apps-cs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://loyolachicagobooks.github.io/systems-handbook-hugo/docs/department-services/google-apps-cs/</guid><description>
&lt;p>The CS and Mathematics departments subscribe to Google Apps for Your
Domain. Among other things, we can host sites, e-mail, documents,
calendaring, etc. Our primary use at the moment is for Google Sites,
which allows individuals, workgroups (e.g. project teams in classes),
research groups, and other collaborations to host their own private or
public web sites. While this software is officially in beta, it's
already proving to be a winner for many needs. Moreover, we can assign
you your own hostname within one of the 3 domains. Examples include
&lt;a href="http://www.etl.luc.edu">www.etl.luc.edu&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="http://gkt.etl.luc.edu">gkt.etl.luc.edu&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="http://doty.math.luc.edu">doty.math.luc.edu&lt;/a>, and
&lt;a href="http://tonyg.math.luc.edu">tonyg.math.luc.edu&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We reserve the right to terminate any Google site that contains
inappropriate content or is reported to Google or us as being offensive.
So we ask that if you have such uses in mind to consider setting up your
own Google Site that is not connected to LUC or the department proper.
We are not generally taking advantage of e-mail and other services at
this time and reserve these address for faculty and researchers
officially connected to the department. To request a Google Site or
other service, please see &lt;code>getting-help&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;ldquo;doc&amp;rdquo;}.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>