<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Loyola CS Systems Guide – labs</title><link>/tags/labs/</link><description>Recent content in labs on Loyola CS Systems Guide</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/labs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Facilities</title><link>/docs/department-services/facilities/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/department-services/facilities/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="general-computing-labs">General Computing Labs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The department has general computer laboratories at the Lake Shore and
Water Tower Campuses. They are three windows labs and one free/open
source laboratory (at Water Tower Campus only) running Ubuntu Linux. The
Windows labs are managed by Information Technology Services (ITS) with
software requests submitted regularly by the department.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>::: index
pair: research; Internet-2
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="internet-2">Internet-2&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The CS Department was part of a successful team that received funding to
bring Internet-2 to Loyola University Chicago as a whole. This
next-generation Internet allows students within the department to
explore ideas such as cluster computing, grid computing, Internet
telephony, and distributed scientific application development. In
addition to Internet-2, the university maintains a high-speed optical
network/ring that connects all of the Loyola campuses (LSC, WTC, and
Loyola University Medical Center).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>::: index
pair: research; Windows HPC Cluster
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="windows-hpc-cluster">Windows HPC Cluster&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Drs. Putonti and Thiruvathukal operate two Windows HPC clusters: an
80-node dual-core Opteron cluster by Rackable Systems and a 24-node
dual-core Xeon cluster by Dell. Both clusters feature high-speed
Ethernet and/or Infiniband. These clusters are housed in the ITS data
center.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>::: index
pair: research; GPGPU pair: Emerging Technologies Laboratory; GPGPU
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="gpgpu-server">GPGPU Server&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Our new GPGPU Server was set up at our ETL. It is SuperServer
7046GT-TRF-TC4 with 2 x Intel Xeon Quad-Core (16 logical processors),
96GB RAM, 4 x NVIDIA® Tesla C2075 GPUs. Please read our
&lt;code>gpgpu-server&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;ldquo;doc&amp;rdquo;} guide on how to get
started.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>::: index
single: Emerging Technologies Laboratory
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="emerging-technologies-laboratory">Emerging Technologies Laboratory&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://www.etl.luc.edu">ETL&lt;/a> is a growing presence for experimental
computer science and engineering projects. This laboratory supports many
experimental computing needs and is a place where students can explore
ideas not covered directly in any particular class. Virtualization,
embedded systems, green computing, and mobile development take place
here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>::: index
single: wireless
:::&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="wireless">Wireless&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The entire department (faculty offices, computer labs, emerging
technologies lab, and halls) are covered by 802.11g Wireless LAN.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="research-data-center">Research Data Center&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Loyola University Chicago&amp;rsquo;s Research Data Center (RDC) is a
1,000-square-foot facility dedicated to support research and funded
grants projects, provides a secure home for the computational clusters
and related equipment used by our research community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The RDC (opened in 2010) delivers a high availability computing
environment for research projects. This facility is equipped with power
protection, including an uninterruptible power supply and a back-up
generator. Multiple computer room air conditioner (CRAC) units provide
redundant cooling for the space, and a structured cabling design allows
for high-speed network connectivity. In addition to fire protection,
additional safety and security elements for the RDC include keycard
access, camera surveillance, and environmental monitoring.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sized to accommodate moderate growth, several research initiatives are
currently taking advan- tage of the space, which at present houses three
research clusters and over 100 nodes. Additionally, collaborative
research efforts with other participating institutions and/or
organizations have full access and connectivity to Internet2 via the
Metropolitan Research &amp;amp; Education Network (MREN) to accommodate high
bandwidth applications, data transmissions, and computational require-
ments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A steering committee, made up of senior administrators, faculty, and ITS
professionals, is re- sponsible for reviewing, evaluating, and
recommending strategies, plans, and policies governing the use of the
RDC resources. Loyola&amp;rsquo;s RDC is managed by Information Technology
Services (ITS) in partnership with the university&amp;rsquo;s Facilities
Department.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Drs. Thiruvathukal, Läufer, and Putonti have a general-purpose 80-node
computing cluster that runs a mix of Windows HPC Server and the ROCKS
clustering software.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs: Windows Labs</title><link>/docs/its-services/windows-labs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/its-services/windows-labs/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;/div>
&lt;h1 id="windows-labs">Windows Labs&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>With our partner, Loyola Information Technology Services (ITS), we
ensure that CS and Math/Stats software needs are formally requested from
ITS. This allows us to focus on advanced computing needs (in particular,
Linux and server-side applications) and ensure ubiquitous access to
Windows labs via the Loyola login ID.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Faculty may request additional software by visiting
&lt;a href="http://www.luc.edu/its/resources/technologypurchases/hardwaresoftwarereviewprocess/">ITS&lt;/a>,
or by sending an e-mail to the &lt;em>windows&lt;/em> alias (see
&lt;code>getting-help&lt;/code>{.interpreted-text role=&amp;ldquo;doc&amp;rdquo;}). In the latter case, the
lab manager (Miao Ye) will fill in a software request on your behalf.
You are encouraged to submit requests one month before the end of the
current term, if you need the software in the summer or following term.
For example, if you need software in Fall 2009, consider getting your
request in by April of 2008 (one month before the Spring 2008 term
ends). You should also indicate in your request whether you are willing
to help test the software after it becomes available. We cannot be held
responsible for late requests or requests that do not have a designated
faculty member interested in testing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Again, because the Windows hardware and software are now maintained by
ITS, we ask that all issues you encounter be reported, no matter how
trivial. If you discover broken hardware and/or software, use the &lt;a href="http://www.luc.edu/helpdesk/">ITS
Help Desk&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>