<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Loyola CS Systems Guide – remote</title><link>https://softwaresystemslaboratory.github.io/SSL-Hugo-Website/tags/remote/</link><description>Recent content in remote on Loyola CS Systems Guide</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://softwaresystemslaboratory.github.io/SSL-Hugo-Website/tags/remote/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Remote Access</title><link>https://softwaresystemslaboratory.github.io/SSL-Hugo-Website/docs/how-to/remoteaccess/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://softwaresystemslaboratory.github.io/SSL-Hugo-Website/docs/how-to/remoteaccess/</guid><description>
&lt;p>All users of our systems can access their files remotely; however, we
currently do not provide general support to students or faculty for
Samba and CIFS shares (i.e. mounting as a Windows drive) owing largely
to security and usability considerations. (There is a legacy Samba
setup; however, no support is provided.) There are a number of
alternatives to Windows shares that we do support and consider effective
for most needs.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="sshfs">sshfs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you are a Linux or Mac user, you can use the Secure Shell Filesystem
client, which makes use of the Fuse project. Linux users can simply
install the sshfs package (e.g., on Ubuntu: &lt;code>apt-get install sshfs&lt;/code>).
The Dokan project on Windows provides the same capabilities as sshfs on
Linux and the Mac.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="secure-ftp-sftp">Secure FTP (sftp)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Most Secure Shell clients have the ability to upload/download files. If
you are looking for something that is less transparent than a typical
filesystem and can live with an upload/download model, this might be all
you need (and seemingly, is what most of our users want).&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="version-control-systems">Version Control Systems&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We recommend that all of our students learn how to use the Concurrent
Versioning System (CVS) or Subversion, especially for programming
classes. Source code management is available through command-line tools
or nicely integrated into many development environments, such as Eclipse
and NetBeans (even Visual Studio supports Subversion through the AnkhSVN
add-in). The TortoiseSVN and TortoiseHg clients for Windows are
particularly nice!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="gnome-and-kde">Gnome and KDE&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you are an Ubuntu desktop user at home, both of these UIs allow you
to connect to a remote place via SSH and browse folders as part of the
UI's shell (that is, you don't need to go to the dreaded terminal). In
Gnome, Places -&amp;gt; Connect to Server will allow a user to connect to a
ssh server and will then treat that connection to your home directory
like a mounted drive.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="putty-and-cygwin">PuTTY and Cygwin&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Speaking of SSH access, Windows users are encouraged to use the PuTTY or
Cygwin support for SSH. There are a number of good commercial solutions
but these cost big money (between $75-$100) and are not likely to be
cost effective (let alone necessary) for most members of our community.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="unison">Unison&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Unison is an excellent 2-way file synchronization tool. It supports all
platforms.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>