<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Loyola CS Systems Guide – content management</title><link>/tags/content-management/</link><description>Recent content in content management on Loyola CS Systems Guide</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/content-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Docs: Content Management</title><link>/docs/department-services/content-management-and-hosting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/department-services/content-management-and-hosting/</guid><description>
&lt;div class="pageinfo pageinfo-primary">
&lt;p>We no longer provide support for static web page serving, PHP, and CGI
scripting. We realize that this might be an inconvenience to some.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="temporary-hosting-using-a-vm">Temporary Hosting using a VM&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For students doing project work, we can provide temporary virtual machines running on VMWare or Windows Hyper-V.
These VMs can be configured with a web server that is visible internally to Loyola.
See &lt;a href="../virtualization/">Virtualization&lt;/a> for additional information.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="alternatives">Alternatives&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We encourage those who need to set up web sites to consider establishing
web hosting account via one of the many providers out there.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="blogging-platforms">Blogging platforms&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you are just looking to maintain a simple site that allows for page creation and blog posts, the best options are blogging platforms, such as &lt;a href="https://wordpress.com">Wordpress&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://ghost.org">Ghost&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://micro.blog">Micro.Blog&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="linode">Linode&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We actually use dedicated virtual machines for some department hosting needs. A particularly nice option is &lt;a href="https://linode.com">Linode&lt;/a>. For as little as $5-$10 a month, you can get a dedicated virtual machine with any Linux distribution you like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This option is primarily for more technical users who know Unix/Linux system administration (and commands).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="google-apps">Google Apps&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We do have Google Apps available in the department, which includes Blogger and Google Sites. While both of these options are starting to look/feel a bit dated, they nevertheless are easy to use and require virtually no configuration (except for us to enable your site).&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>